foreign
[Music]
here's an intriguing number pattern one
plus two is three
four plus five plus six is seven plus
eight
nine plus ten plus eleven plus twelve
is 13 plus 14 plus 15 and 16 plus 17
plus 18 plus 19 plus 20 is 21 plus 22
plus 23 plus 24 and so on this pattern
continues as long as we take it out the
question I have for you is can you
determine the general pattern and the
general formula and if so can you
provide a proof that this formula always
holds pause the video and give it a try
[Music]
if you need a hint the first term and
every sum on the left is of the form N
squared for an integer n
in the first term in every sum on the
right is of the form N squared plus n
plus 1 for the same value of n let's
investigate A visual representation of
these sums in order to uncover the
formula Take N squared times n plus 1
cubes and place them in a cuboid with
Dimensions n by n plus 1 by n on top of
this cuboid place a triangular array of
cubes with a base of length n this adds
an extra n times n plus 1 divided by two
cubes on top of the cuboid foreign
[Music]
utilizing this structure in two
different ways will reveal the formula
that we want if we first separate the
structure into horizontal arrays like
this we see that all of the green
rectangular arrays are n by n
so there is a total number of N squared
plus N squared plus 1 up to N squared
plus n cubes on the left on the other
hand if we separate the structure
vertically we end up with rectangular
arrays of the size n plus 1 by n with
cubes on top so there's a total of N
squared plus n plus one up to N squared
plus n plus n total cubes on the right
side
therefore the formula that we're looking
for says that the sum of the numbers
from N squared to N squared plus n is
equal to the sum of the numbers from N
squared plus n plus 1 up to N squared
plus 2N